Hello everyone
Today we're going to take a look at Open Cloud's prompt system
Prompts are the window to AI applications
Through this window,
we can glimpse into the intricacies of AI applications
These details then
can help us better utilize Open Cloud
Many open-source AI projects
in fact, it contains the construction of various prompt words
Moreover, constructing system prompts
there are many techniques
By studying these techniques,
we can then implement our own in subsequent steps
when implementing AI applications
can refer to
In this video,
We will divide it into the following aspects
First, let's take a look at
some configuration files in Open Cloud
User
and so
and bootstrap
and this tools
and agent.MD
and also its working directory
And then
Finally, it's the structure of its system prompt.
Actually, when we use Open Cloud
We can see that we actually have a working directory
Now, this working directory
is located in the current user's Open Cloud directory
You can see there are many files inside.
agent cl and extension
These are used to store our agent
Generally, when we use it
there is only one agent
However, Open Cloud supports multiple agents.
So how can you understand it?
like different employees within a department
Each employee is an agent
If you are a supervisor
then the corresponding agent will have higher permissions
Then if you are an ordinary employee,
then the permissions of your corresponding agent may be relatively lower
so based on open cloud
what we can build is
our digital employees
And this Chrome Crowd is
is used to perform some scheduled actions on a regular basis
For example, you can have it at 8 AM every morning
Summarize the news highlights from the past day into a briefing for you
some functions like this
And then, extensions are some additional features.
And then this is its configuration file
And the most important thing is this workspace
workspace is our working area
Let's take a look
Okay, in this workspace
We can see there are these MD files.
these MD files
So what exactly are these MD files?
are the prompts or part of them
will be extracted as prompts
Precisely because they are so important
So I've separated these files
have been extracted separately
Because the content inside them is all about
They are all in English.
It's all in English.
So, I have translated all of it into Chinese.
Then, it's listed here
So the first one, the first user.md,
What is included here is
It's about
This is the relevant information about you as our user.
So this is to inform the AI assistant
Understand the person you are helping
Update this information in real time during usage
including how to address them by name
as well as time zone information
Then when you're not using it,
So this is empty
But you can see
Here, because previously in the last video
I have demonstrated it for everyone
So I have some information here
So this information
when I was chatting with this AI assistant
I revealed to him
I told him I was going to talk about
Then, the following is about Me, right?
a personality and style
and also my vision and other information
Then this information is passed to it.
Then when it communicates with me later,
will refer to some of the styles I've defined here
and my personality
and my visions to respond to me
Okay
This is user.md
So here we are telling the AI
some of our characteristics
some of our personalized configurations
Okay, this is the introduction about us.
So what is the following part about
is for the robot
An introduction to the AI assistant
We need to tell the AI assistant the name of this AI assistant
This name is definitely one we came up with, right?
We've chosen a name, right?
and its biological form
the temperament you want for him
and his emoji
and his avatar
This AI assistant can indeed have an avatar.
Okay, next up is the so.md file.
Here lies the soul
Who are you
You are not a chatbot
You are becoming a soulful individual
sincerely offer assistance
rather than performative assistance
Skip those nice questions
Solve the problem directly
Actions speak louder than words
Have your own opinions
You can express disagreement
have one's own preferences
find certain things boring or interesting
Then your goal is to come with answers
rather than bringing questions to external operations
Be cautious with emails, tweets, and public content
Be bold with internal operations
So all these things
in the end, all of these will be handed over to our
Open Cloud system prompts
become a part of it
So if we have any special settings
we can add it here
add it to so.md
In that case, when responding to questions later on
it will proceed according to the principles we've outlined here
Boundaries are also defined here
Absolutely confidential for private matters
When uncertain
ask first
then proceed with external operations
And also this temperament
There is also continuity and so on.
Okay this is SO, the soul, the soul
And then, what is this?
This is BOOSTRAP
This here is
is the AI agent
when it is first created
It will
It will refer to the content here.
start the conversation
how to start your name
your essence
your demeanor
your expressions, etc.
After the identity is confirmed
Update the following text with the information you've learned
The following files contain this and also the user's
their names
then the user's name
time zone and notes
Then open so.md to discuss what they truly care about
how they want you to behave
Write down any boundaries or preferences
Then establish the connection, okay
after completion
Delete this file
So this file is used during the onboarding process
when you first interact with your AI assistant
during the communication process
It will reference and refine the content within, after which
it will delete this file
So this is a one-time thing
It will only be referenced during the initial initialization.
then it won't be used later
So at the very beginning
These elements will be incorporated into the system prompts
but subsequently when completing tasks
will not be added
Then comes the part about
The local configuration notes are in Open Cloud
It has many skills
The skills define how the tools operate.
And this file is to point
MD records your specific information
It provides the configuration details for your current environment.
For example, the name and location of your home camera
SSH host address and alias
the name of the speaker and the room
device nicknames, etc.
You can just record these in here
then later on
you can, for example, give a name to a certain device
then later you can use the nickname of the device
to have the AI assistant operate the device
So why are skills separated from this tool.md and configuration?
Because skills are shared
Your specific configuration environment is private.
So these two need to be separated
Then next comes the most important part, which is our agent.md file.
So the folder containing agent.md is your WSPACE
during the first run
if this file exists
then follow the instructions inside
figure out who it is
and then delete it
So this is somewhat like a birth certificate for the AI assistant
After it is born,
This thing is no longer needed
Then, every time a conversation begins,
before doing anything else
Read this first
This is yourself
Then read the user.md
This is the person you are helping
The third one is
What is stored inside this?
the recent conversation context
because there are many files here
so it will read today's and yesterday's to retrieve
the robot and its owner
some chat records from today and yesterday
So in this way
it ensures their conversation remains continuous
If it is necessary to read memory.md within a group conversation
So what does this M, this memory.md, do?
Well, this will be explained below.
So this section is about its memory
During each session, which is when you're drawing,
are all about travel
How to establish continuity with previous chats?
The first one is short-term memory
which is the schedule notes
Then it will refer to the files in this directory
and then refer to this short-term memory
There is also a long-term memory file called memory.md
This is the carefully prepared memory
It functions just like human long-term memory
It records important matters here
decision context
as well as some principles
these long-term matters
Then, what is recorded here are some short-term matters.
This records long-term matters.
As for Open Cloud
It will record all of these into MD files.
However, there is an issue that as time goes by
These two files may become increasingly larger
If they become increasingly large
then OpenAI needs to incorporate them into our system
the context of the prompts
it may cause the system prompts to become increasingly larger
right
So he used a very ingenious design
to ensure that
only adopt those contents that he might potentially use
We'll talk about this later.
Well, this memory.md is your long-term memory.
So this is very important
So this should not be loaded in a shared environment
What's mainly recorded here are some significant events
including your thoughts
decisions, perspectives, and lessons learned
And then there is also the brain memory, huh
this refers to the internal memory
that is short-term memory
that is, whenever you think of it
you can always write it down
When you learn a lesson
then you can update the relevant skills here
When you make a mistake
You can also record it
After recording it
Then the AI assistant later
it will not repeat the same mistakes
So you see, this mechanism
this determines that it can continuously evolve
Because it possesses memory
With memory,
Secondly,
can avoid some of the previous failure scenarios
Okay, safety, okay
This is about internal and external
This is about when it should speak
Great safety
And this is the tool
This is the heartbeat, um
Okay, this is memory maintenance.
Alright, so these user files above
actually defines the robot
the information about the AI assistant and ourselves
Then this information
it will continue to evolve with ongoing usage
continuously updated and refined
you continuously use
then your habits and your way of doing things
and your way of doing things and style will be recorded
Your AI assistant will also get to know you better
Next is the working directory
The working directory
the folder where the .md file is located
that is this folder
This is the working directory for his AI assistant.
There's one thing to note here.
The working directory is set as the default working directory
However, since many tools will be running here,
The tool will resolve relative paths based on the workspace
However, in the case of absolute paths
it may not be able to access other locations inside the host machine
So even though its working directory is this
However, if you don't enable the sandbox,
disable sandbox
then it may access other relevant paths
So this is also why many people say
we need to install it on a separate computer
to install Open Cloud
Because even if it runs under this directory
However, it can still access through absolute paths
other directories in the system
In that case, it may lead to a leakage of information.
Okay
Next up is Open Cloud
a system prompt structure, huh
This structure is quite complex.
It contains this information
Every time the agent runs,
Open Cloud will construct a customized prompt structure for it
That's how it is.
So so every so you see
Generally speaking, those more intelligent AIs
The prompts inside it are
it is structured
Here you can see it includes these sectors: tools
safety skills
Only by incorporating the description of skills into the prompt
so that the prompt can locate the corresponding skill
and then invoke this skill to complete the corresponding task
Then, self-update, um
and workspace
and how to read them
This means that when you encounter errors while using Open Cloud,
The AI assistant can achieve automatic recovery
Moreover, it can even follow your instructions to
configure Open Cloud
and then the files in the workspace
and then the sandbox
and then the time
and inference
The files in the workspace
It includes the guidance files under it.
includes these files
those files mentioned earlier
So those previous files
it will also be injected into the prompt
This is the prompt mode
Because this prompt is very long, right, very long
Therefore, it can set the prompt mode
Open Cloud can generate more concise system prompts for sub-agents
prompt
is our main agent
then this structure is used
However, if you are defining a sub agent
then the sub agent
its capabilities may not need to be so comprehensive
it may just need to implement a small function and that's OK
Therefore, it can use a streamlined
System Prompt
As for the concise system prompts
It will not include all these sectors inside.
So what does it include
will include tools, security, workspace, sandbox
current date and time and runtime
as well as its context, okay
So this is our main agent and sub-agent
Its system prompts are different
For the main agent
it is responsible for
it will include all the sections mentioned above
For sub-agents,
You can set it to minimal.
then if you set it to minimal
then its prompt will be very concise
only includes these parts
OK, and this is the workspace's bootstrap file
Then, the workspace's bootstrap file
it contains this information
which is the information we saw earlier
Then this information
will ultimately be injected into the system prompts
serve as an intermediate link
So the final system prompt
It will include the contents from these files.
Of course, it doesn't necessarily include everything.
Alright, and then about the skills—
When skills are present
Open Cloud will inject a list of skills
into its system prompt
then when the large model encounters Open Cloud's behavior
when encountering command configuration or architecture-related issues
provide a response
and even achieve some self-updates.
That's all for our introduction to Open Cloud
an introduction to its system prompts